

Sameer Kamran

(+49) 1774052203 | me@sameerkamran.de | sameerkamran.de |

https://github.com/smrkamran

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sameer-kamran-dev/ | Frankfurt, Germany

About me:

Software Engineer with more than 4 years of professional experience in software industry. Worked as a lone-wolf as well as in Agile Teams. Expertise is design and development of Frontend Applications as well as WebApis from scratch. Also designed databases and have been part of requirement gathering teams. Always open to learn new tools and technologies. Looking for new opportunities and challenges to showcase my skills and to learn more in my field.

SKILLS

Backend

.Net Core 2.x, 3.x. | Asp .Net MVC5 | FluentValidation | SignalR | AutoMapper | AutoFac | NUnit | EF | EFCore | NLog | ExpressJS | Laravel | Java Spring

Frontend

Angular 2+ | RxJS | Jasmine | ReactJS | Aurelia | JQuery | KnockoutJS | Angular Material | Material UI | PrimeNG | Bootstrap

Cloud Services

AWS: EC2 | Elastic Beanstalk | RDS | CloudWatch | IAM | S3

Others

GIT, SVN | JIRA, Confluence | Asana

WORK EXPERIENCE

06/2021 - CURRENT - Munich

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - SCHWARM TECHNOLOGIES GMBH

- Working on highly scalable IOT Web Platform
- My responsibilites also includes developing the custom applications for different Energy Companies in Germany like E.On and Nordex.
- Tools I am using are Angular, Aurelia, Java Spring

06/2019 - 06/2021 - Lahore

FULL STACK DEVELOPER - BOLTECH SOLUTIONS

- Worked on Tax Management System for Government of Malawi, Africa (.Net MVC5, SQL Server, SignalR, AutoMapper, Autofac, Angular 6, Angular Material, PrimeNg)
- Worked on GYM Management System for UFC Gym International (.Net Core 3.0, MySQL, SignalR, AutoMapper, Autofac, Angular 8, Angular Material, ZKTeco Access Gates Integration)
- Worked on Employee Service Catalogue & Digital Approvals System for Exceed IT Services (ExpressJS, Mongoose, MongoDB, Angular 7)

.NET DEVELOPER - CODILITY SOLUTIONS

- Worked on Purchase Order Management Web Application (.Net Core 2.1 WebApi, SQL Server, .Net MVC5, KnockoutJS, VanillaJS, SQL Server)
- Worked on Inventory/Point-of-Sale Desktop Application (WPF, SQLite, MvvmCross, DevExpress)
- Worked on Office Management System. Attendance/Task Management (.Net MVC5, SQL Server, SignalR, ZKTeco Biometric Integration)

02/2019 - 06/2019 - Lahore

WEB DEVELOPER (PART TIME) - HIGHBIT TECHNOLOGIES

 Revamped a Mobile Repair Shop POS System (NodeJS, Sequelize, GraphQL, Angular 7, Angular Material)

08/2017 - 02/2018 - Lahore

FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPER - UPWORK

- Worked on a Digital Magazine Website (.Net MVC5, SQL Server, Bootstrap, JQuery)
- Resolved RabbitMQ exchange issue in HR Portal
- Built Custom Chat for NopCommerce Website

04/2017 - 07/2017 - Lahore

.NET DEVELOPER (INTERNSHIP) - INSEPARABLE TECHNOLOGY PVT. LTD.

• Worked on an Ecommerce Store (.Net MVC5, SQL Server, SignalR, OAuth, Social Media Integration)

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

10/2020 - CURRENT - Koblenz, Germany

MASTERS WEB & DATA SCIENCE - Universität Koblenz · Landau

10/2013 - 12/2017 - Lahore, Pakistan

BS INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY - University of the Punjab

03/2017 - 07/2017 - Lahore, Pakistan

CERTIFIED .NET SPECIALIST - E-Venture Solutions

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **URDU**

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	C2	C1	C1	C1	B2
GERMAN	A1	A1	A1	A1	A1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user